Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
There are no
weekends on a ranch.
The routine of Wednesday
is the routine of Saturday.
And the chores of Tuesday
are still chores on Sunday.
Though the banker and bookkeeper
may be tethered to a calendar.
ranchers are bound
only to the seasons.
and note the milestones
of their lives by saying.
"We were married in the spring."
or "She was born in the fall."
or perhaps. "On the hottest
day in the driest summer
ever to plague Montana. my
husband returned to me."
- What is it?
- It's Jack.
They're back.
Cara. they're back!
- Yes. I see.
I'd love to have that
girl's energy just once.
- Not me.
Looks like you got
a runner. there. Jack.
- Problem is she's a faller.
Better go get her. son.
Before she's up standing at
the alter with a busted nose.
- Better get her.
Jack. Before I do.
- You'd never catch me.
- Whoa!
- Woo!
- Hey. don't we got a rule about
running horses to the barn?
The whole
world's got a rule
about running
horses to the barn.
I guess we're the one renegade
outfit that don't pay attention.
- Everyone's gonna pay attention
next time we want to walk
'em back to the barn.
- We'll have that argument
when it comes. Zane.
- It's just stupid.
- It's stupid if your
wife ain't standing there
wondering why
everyone's in a hurry
to get back to the
ranch but you. Ya!
- Running to your
wife is one thing.
but running to that damn barn...
I run the hell out of this
horse to see my family. too.
they're just not standing
at that Goddamn
barn waiting for me.
- If you try to
jump from that horse
and run you're going
to break something.
- My running dismount
days are over. darlin'.
It's a long way down. and this
old man's gonna climb it slow.
Racing across the field to me.
Taking lessons from my nephew.
That one seemed worth trying.
- It's effective.
- Yeah.
- I was worried about
this trip. you know?
I don't know why. It
really worried me.
- We had some trouble.
I'll see the sheriff tomorrow
and talk him through it.
- You just got home. You're
going into town already?
- How 'bout we all go to town?
- Missed you. sweetheart.
- Me. too. Me. too.
- Yeah.
- Where's your horse?
- Henry. Go to Campbells.
Bring Frank here.
Then go to the Archers.
Now. boy. go!
Ah...
- Banner. my God.
What happened?
- The fucking Duttons happened.
It's called
the Hotpoint Automatic.
I wasn't looking there.
There sure is
a lotta cars here.
- So are you selling
electricity in the valley?
- Yes. ma'am.
We will run the cable as they
pave the road to the park.
- You say they're paving
the road to the park?
- All the way from
Canada to Mexico.
- What is that?
- That's a washing machine.
- What does it wash?
- Clothes.
- Oh!
- Can you imagine?
- How?
- Well. an electric
motor spins a cylinder
as water is pumped
through the machine.
Soap is added here and the
agitation removes any soiling.
- Hm.
- What does that wash?
- That's a refrigerator.
The top compartment
keeps food frozen
and the bottom compartment
maintains a temperature
of 38 degrees.
- And you sell these?
- We rent them.
- So you sell electricity.
and then you rent all the
things that need electricity.
- More or less.
- But we don't need
any of these things.
- Well. they're conveniences.
Their use gives you
time to do other things.
- What other things?
- Well... Like other chores.
- Until you invent machines to
do those. then what do we do?
Go on a picnic.
- Go for a swim.
You can go to the cinema.
You can enjoy a
more leisurely life.
- But that ain't more leisurely
because we gotta work more
to pay for all this stuff.
- He's got you there.
- This is the future.
Every home in New York
City has electricity.
They have refrigerators.
and some even have
electric stoves.
- No here's the thing.
we buy all this stuff.
we're not working for
ourselves anymore.
We're working for you.
- The washing machine seems
like a good idea. I must admit.
- It is the future. ma'am.
- Hmph.
How are you sir?
Jacob. you
can't be hanging people
out in the woods
like that no more.
This ain't no cowboy justice.
- What should I
have done different?
- You should've
brought them here.
- Where they'd just get
lynched and hung anyway.
I just saved a mob the trouble.
I hung my share of men with you
standing right beside me. Bill.
- We got a big enough problem
with them cattle thieves
out of Wyoming. we
don't need a range war
with the sheep herders.
- They run their
sheep on my ground.
and then they attacked us
when we came upon them.
Range war's already begun.
You get some deputies up there
and you keep them sum-bitches
on their own land.
or I'll do it.
And you've seen how I do it.
Oh.
- Hey.
- By God. Jake. If this is
progress you can have it.
I've walked six blocks and
you're the first person I know.
- You gotta put
town in the category
of "things you do
for your wife."
- Hell. my wife won't
even come to town anymore.
- I'll admit a fondness
for some of the soda shops.
- Well. you are Irish.
- How's your herd?
- Skinny. Driest
I ever seen it.
How's yours?
- I took 'em high.
- Damn sheepers grazed
off all the high ground.
whether it's their
ground or not.
- I'm working on that.
- Well. if you need any
help. you let me know.
- If I do. it's gonna be
the roughest kind of help.
- Rough is what those
sons of bitches need.
Best to your family.
- And to yours.
- Jacob.
Jacob. I swear to God
you'll get yourself killed
by one of them motor wagons.
Listen. it's too
late to head back.
We're stuck here for the night.
- I got rooms at the hotel.
- Yes. but what about supper?
- Well. they have supper. too.
- There's twenty of us.
- 14 of who can be on their own.
- Got rooms booked
at the Hotel Bozeman.
We leave first thing.
- What would you like to do?
- Well. what would
you like to do?
- Listen to the music
and watch the sunset.
Then go back to the hotel and...
let someone wait on me for once.
- We can do that.
- I don't know. Jack.
this don't look like it.
- He said third
door down the alley.
This is the third door.
- What do you want?
- Umbrellas?
- I told you this
place was real. Dennis.
- I ain't seen nothing that
convinces me yet. Jack.
- Don't you worry.
you just wait.
- This is wild. Jack.
Absolutely wild.
I feel like I'm
back in the city.
- You are in the city.
- Bozeman isn't a city.
- Sure feels like one in here.
- Hey. where'd all
these people come from?
- Back East. I think.
Whoop it up in town. and
vacation in the park.
- How do all these Easterners
know about this place
and I just heard of it?
- What'll you have?
- What do you got?
- We got it all.
- What are the fancy
folks drinking?
- Gin Rickeys for the men and
Bees Knees for the ladies.
- We'll do that. Four of each.
- Cheers.
- Cheers. y'all.
- Do you know this dance?
I don't even know this song.
- I want to try it.
I want to try it. Jack.
- I think she wants to try it.
- I think you better try it.
- Yeah. I think I should.
- Get out there. cowboy. Whoo!
- Ain't that hard.
- Wait.
Wait.
I promise... I promise
I'm worth the wait.
- These damn fingers.
My plan was a beguiling
pose on the bed.
I've fumbled the
moment. I'm afraid.
- You haven't fumbled anything.
- I'm dizzy.
- Me too.
- A crafty bugger.
Unlike a lion that stalks
or a leopard that ambushes.
these hyenas will do both.
Stalks a man down
at the latrine.
followed another into his tent.
One man was killed five miles
from here while surveying
ten feet from his car in
the middle of the day.
No pattern to it.
- You try baiting it?
- I've had a goat
tied to a tree so long
we bring it food and water now.
It's been tied there a week.
It's not as though there's
a food shortage here.
- She's either
old or she's hurt.
And it's just one.
it's not a pack.
- A pack would eat
a man to the bone.
These are just killed.
barely eaten at all.
Like it's fun for her.
We build the fires up at night
and I have men patrolling
in groups of three.
My biggest worry is that
hyena drags a man down
and lions stumble upon it.
Then a whole pride
has a taste for us.
- When do my guides get here?
- Should have been
here yesterday.
- How far is their village?
- Ten miles. maybe.
- They had any attacks up there?
- Don't know.
I wish I knew more. but if
I did I'd be the hunter.
Don't wander far.
- It doesn't look real.
Like I walked into a painting.
- It's an odd place.
Nothing as beautiful
as when the sun rises
or right before it sets.
but in the middle of the day
when the sun beats this place
like a hammer.
- Do you believe Darwin
saying we come from monkeys.
and all mankind
began right here?
- I can show you a place with
the footprints of a child
baked into the lava rock.
I don't know where we came from.
but we've been here
since stone was soft.
- Long time.
- In America. if you
walk up on an animal.
they run away from you.
Don't matter what it is...
a wolf. a deer. bear...
but here. they look at you
like you're a nuisance.
Something that's been harassing
'em for a million years.
Hm. We probably have.
- Are the footprints far?
- Not too far.
- Show me.
- What are those?
- Impala.
- They look like goats.
- They probably are.
- I want to ask you something.
- Ask away.
- Been giving it a
lot of thought...
- This sounds ominous.
- Alexandra's just too
long. Just in general.
- You don't like my name.
- It's beautiful. it's just.
if I need to yell at
you or something...
- Why would you
need to yell at me?
- Not at you. but
in your direction.
Like if there's a. you know.
there's a lion or something.
If I say. "Alexandra. look
out there's a lion." it's...
- If there's a lion don't even
use my name. just say "lion."
- It's just a mouthful is the
deal. and I was just hoping
I could call you Alex.
- Then call me Alex.
- Good deal.
- I'm glad we worked that out.
- Mm-hm.
Well. if it was that hard
to ask about a nickname.
I won't hold my
breath for a proposal.
- Proposal?
- I must say. you appeared
much smarter at the bar.
A marriage
proposal.
I won't hold my breath.
- Hell. I'll ask
you that right now.
I mean it.
- I think this affair might
need to mature beyond a day.
- Why?
What for?
Are you worried there's things
about me you might not like?
I can promise you.
there's plenty.
- I don't hear a question.
- Marry me.
- That's a statement.
- It's a demand.
- You Americans are brutes.
- Yes. ma'am.
- I will.
I'll marry you.
Now. I would like to
see these footprints
from the dawn of man. hm?
Unless you need to cross
"naming our children"
off the list as well.
- We should give
it some thought.
Thank you.
Let's go.
You're right. it's a
child. All alone out here.
There's no toes.
- Maybe we didn't
have toes back then.
Maybe he was wearing sandals.
- I've never felt small before.
I've never felt like my life...
Our time here is an eye blink.
It's one exhaled breath
and then we're gone.
- That's why I'm not
wasting any time with you.
- They don't look real to me.
They look like God just looked
at shapes in the clouds and...
made animals out of 'em.
That's how much sense
they make to me.
- When I first saw you. all
I saw was this sullen man.
I see the boy in you now.
I see our boy in you.
- I see him in you.
- My parents are going
to fucking hate you.
- Mine are gonna love you.
- You have parents?
I fancied you just crawled
from the wilds of America.
I rather like my version better.
- Alex. give me your hand.
Alex?
Give me your hand.
It's okay. give me
your hand. come on.
Here you go. come on.
There you go. there you go.
right there. Right there.
There you go. come on.
- Understand why you
shortened it to Alex. now.
Much more efficient.
- Good. Help me. help me.
Alex?
Help me. Ready?
Push.
Okay. hang on. Hang on.
- What now?
- We can't walk out
here. Not at night.
Besides. we just rang a
fourteen-ton dinner bell.
We need to get up that tree.
- Wouldn't it be safer
to stay in the truck?
- Darling. there is nothing
safe about this truck. Come on.
There you go.
Jesus.
For moments like these.
- I must admit.
I had a different vision
of how our day would end.
- It's not funny.
- Darlin'. there aren't
words to describe the pickle
we just found ourselves in.
- Is it bad?
- We need a higher tree.
- This is the
highest tree around.
- That's the pickle.
- What do we do?
- We'll wait here till morning.
And we pray that a pride
of lions or a leopard
don't want up this tree. either.
- You think they'd want up
the tree while we're in it?
- We're the reason that
they'd want up the tree.
- Hmm.
Plan to share that? Thank you.
Mm.
- It's even more
beautiful from here.
This could be our last night.
- I won't let it.
- But it could.
- What is that?
- Hyenas.
- No sound.
- Are they gone?
- It's gonna be this all night.
- Oh. God!
Spencer?
- We're here!
We're here!
We're here.
- Spencer?
- Up the tree!
- Good God. man.
- Tell me about it.
Give me your hand.
I'm going to send
Alex down to you.
- Alex?
- My fiancé.
At least she was
a few hours ago.
You still my fiancé?
- We'll talk about
it in the car.
- Take this.
- Thank you.
- You're not out
of the bush yet.
Any chance you'd care
to climb down now?
There's a pride of lions
not fifty feet from me.
- Coming.
Here.
- My God. man. I'll
buy you another rope.
- No. This one's lucky.
- I looked death in the eye and
I didn't feel alive. Spencer.
I only felt horror.
- But you felt.
I never said it
was gonna be fun.
I just said you'd feel.
- I don't want to
feel like that.
Do you understand me?
I don't ever want to
feel like that again.
- For a long time that was
the only way I could feel.
Till I met you.
And I don't ever want to
feel that way again. either.
- It's settled then.
Tomorrow you'll find a new job.
- Honey. that wasn't my job.
That was just you and me
taking a drive in the country.
- Perhaps I should
alter my perspective.
The price of making love
under the sun twice in a day
is being attacked
by a pride of lions.
- Three times.
Day's not over yet.
I feel
I should point out that
I can hear every
word you both say.
- Then you understand why I'm
asking you to drive faster.
- Or just have sex in
the back of my auto.
Why not.
- Morning.
- You want in here?
- No.
Just watching.
- Not sure this
is worth watching.
- Oh. it's worth watching.
After all these years. it's
still worth watching...
You could watch
me too. I suppose.
You know it's all the rage now.
Women shaving... their
legs. beneath their arms.
- Interesting fad. to be sure.
- I wonder what that says
about us. as a species.
I mean it's not as if women
were running a straight razor
down their legs a decade ago.
They invented a razor
specifically for women
when no need for one existed.
then invented the need.
As if selling razors to half
the population wasn't enough.
What?
- I didn't say a word.
- But don't you find it curious?
- I'm not curious.
It's greed. That's it.
- Exactly. That's
exactly my point.
What does that say
about us. as a species?
- We've been married
for 40 years...
- Forty-four.
- Okay. I'm rounding down
to make us feel younger.
Well.
that's not working.
- And in all those years.
you've have never
asked me a question
that you did not
have the answer to.
- Ah. I have an answer.
- I know.
- Care to hear it?
- I can't wait to hear it.
- It will be the
thing that ends us.
Greed will be the thing
that kills us all.
- I'm sure you're right.
Now what do you really
want to talk about?
- Oh... nothing. really.
I just wanted to talk
and I wanted you to
listen and you did.
I wonder if you know
how rare that is.
- I know how rare you are.
Which is it is a
pleasure and a joy
to listen to you babble
on about utter nonsense.
It's not nonsense.
One day women will be
shaving between their legs
because some razor company
told them to. you watch.
- I won't be there
to watch. Breakfast?
- Breakfast be lovely.
- Jacob?
Jacob... What are you doing?
- I was just wondering
who this old man is
staring at me in the mirror?
When the hell did that happen?
- Never seen that man before.
- We run out of pavement.
you walk these horses.
I don't want you rattling
these ladies to death.
- Yes. sir.
- We'll ride with the wagon
Y'all get back to the ranch.
- Let me leave a few
cowboys with you.
- You're riding in front.
If there's any trouble.
you'll run into it first.
- Yes. sir.
Let's go.
- Here ya go.
- Finally. some clouds.
And maybe some rain.
- We need rain.
We just don't need it while
we're sitting in this buggy.
- We need rain and we ain't
choosy about when God brings it.
Better bring it soon.
- Whoa. whoa. whoa.
- Shooting from this direction.
- Yep.
- Get out of the wagon!
Get out of the wagon. now!
Now!
Get out of the wagon!
- Jack! Jack!
- Help!
- Son of a bitch.
Jack! Jack!
Jack!
- Whoa. whoa. whoa!
Go!
- Shooting stopped.
- They're mounting up.
- Here they come.
Mind your ammo.
- Stay down. Stay down.
Damn it!
- Jake...
- Jacob.
Jake Dutton!
I'm a man of my word!
- Run.
- You're shot.
- We both are.
- Go after that buggy.
We're gonna need it.
- Jacob!
- John! John!
- No. no. You don't
want to see this.
- See what?
- Jacob...
Just breathe.
- Wait. Wait! Just wait!
Hell is where you'll go
if you do this. ma'am.
All right. take me to
the nearest sheriff
and let him hang me...
That way you'll get your
justice without closing
the gates of Heaven.
- What do you know about Heaven?
[music
- Bedroom?
- Kitchen.
On the table.
Put Elizabeth on that
table over there.
There scissors. top
drawer. Two pair.
Bring them. both of them.
Carl. Carl. through that door on
the left. there's fresh linens.
And a bucket. bring it here.
Thank you.
Ah!
- Here. Here.
Press these against the wounds.
it'll stop the bleeding.
Press hard.
- Jake. you're going to be fine.
- You get 'em all?
- One drove off.
I'll send for the
sheriff first thing.
- No sheriff.
They find out what
they've done to me...
they'll come for this place.
The banks. miners.
The thieves.
No sheriff.
Ah... Cara.
It's no use.
- You're still talking.
You're still breathing.
- Honey...
- I'll not quit.
- Spencer must come home now.
You get him home.
Cara. get him home.
- Lord help us.
You tend to the girl.
You and I begin with him.
Young man. you must
wait your turn.
- Don't worry about me.
- Cara. step back.
Cara. we have no time.
Leave the room!
Now!
Get the morphine.
You there. boil me
some water. right now.
Come around here. put
some pressure on that.
Right there! Yes. hold it.
More pressure. yes.
That's it. that's it.
- "Spencer. your
brother has been killed.
"By the time you
receive this letter.
"I suppose your uncle
has been killed as well.
"Your nephew has been wounded.
"This ranch and your
legacy are in peril.
"War has descended upon
this place and your family.
"Whatever war you fight
within yourself must wait.
You must come home
and fight this one."
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm